through its research activities ,  <ORGANIZATION> Idiap </ORGANIZATION>  pursues its main objective to conduct fundamental research projects at the highest level in its preferred areas , thus taking its place among the best on a national ,  <LOCATION> European </LOCATION>  and global scale . Idiap benefits from a wide network of partners internationally and works actively with large universities , public and private research centers , et cetera .

scientific activities

IM2  <ORGANIZATION> National Centre of Competence in Research </ORGANIZATION>  ( interactive and multimodal management of information systems ) since  <DATE>  two thousand one  </DATE> 

participation in 36 research programs

project management in 8 consortiums

participation in the economic development strategy of the  <LOCATION> Canton </LOCATION>  of  <LOCATION> Valais </LOCATION>  through The Ark program and in particular the IdeArk company

221 scientific publications in  <DATE>  two thousand eleven  </DATE> 

organization of a number of international conferences
